
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Referencing topics</title>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Referencing topics">
    <p>Several semantag-tags needs to identify a topic. Since topicmaps supports various ways to identify topics, we decided to make a generic set of attributes that allow you to specify what topic you mean.</p>
    </section>
    <section name="Attributes">
    <p>The following common attributes allow you to identify a topic unambigously</p>
    <table border="1" cellpadding="3" cellspacing="2" width="100%">
        <tbody>
          <tr class="b">
            <th>Name</th>
            <th>Type</th>
            <th>Description</th>
            <th>Required</th>
            <th>Default</th>
          </tr>
            <tr class="a">
              <td>topic</td>
              <td>org.tm4j.topicmap.Topic</td>
              <td>a topic</td>
              <td>no</td>
              <td></td>
            </tr>
            <tr class="a">
              <td>topicID</td>
              <td>java.lang.String</td>
              <td>the <code>id</code> of a topic. If and how ids are assigned to topics depends on the topicmap engine.</td>
              <td>no</td>
              <td></td>
            </tr>
            <tr class="a">
              <td>topicName</td>
              <td>
              java.lang.String</td>
              <td>the name of a topic. Keep in mind, that names in topicmaps are unique just for a distinct scope. This attribute is not implemented in Semantag 0.1</td>
              <td>no</td>
              <td></td>
            </tr>
            <tr class="a">
              <td>topicSourceLocator</td>
              <td>
              java.lang.String</td>
              <td>identifies a topic by the address of one of its <code>sourceLocator</code></td>
              <td>no</td>
              <td></td>
            </tr>
            <tr class="a">
              <td>topicSubject</td>
              <td>
              java.lang.String</td>
              <td>identifies a topic by the address of its <code>subject</code></td>
              <td>no</td>
              <td></td>
            </tr>
            <tr class="a">
              <td>topicSubjectIndicator</td>
              <td>
              java.lang.String</td>
              <td>identifies a topic by the address of one of its <code>subjectIndicators</code></td>
              <td>no</td>
              <td></td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
      </table>
    </section>
     <section name="Tags">
     <p>The following topics allow the usage of the topic referencing attributes</p>
      <ul>
        <li><a href="org/semantag/tm/AddInstanceOfTag.html">&lt;addInstanceOf&gt;</a> - the topic referencing attributes are used to identify the type</li>
        <li><a href="org/semantag/tm/AddPlayerTag.html">&lt;addPlayer&gt;</a> - the topic referencing attributes are used to identify the player</li>
        <li><a href="org/semantag/tm/AddScopeTag.html">&lt;addScope&gt;</a> - the topic referencing attributes are used to identify the theme</li>
        <li><a href="org/semantag/tm/UseTopicTag.html">&lt;useTopic&gt;</a> the topic referencing attributes are used to identify the topic</li>
      </ul>
      </section>
</body>
</document>